Now we're going to discuss the project
management office PMO, or you might see it
called or hear it called the program
management office.
So the PMO is in place mainly to support
the project managers.
Oh, and you can refer to your PIMBOC on
page 4849 for the PMO information.
So the PMO is set up again to support
project managers.
So they can be considered stakeholders
throughout the life of the project and
will ensure the project aligns with the
business strategic objectives.
So they will help provide
resources, shared resources,
methodologies that will follow,
governance on the projects.
All right.
So let's look at the second slide.
So the PMO will centralize
the coordination of
the project management
and provide best practices.
Again, overall project governance.
And they often ensure compliance,
all right, whether it's with the
organization or federal government
compliance on our projects.
All right.
So they'll standardize the processes for
project management providing
methodologies, templates, procedures,
work instructions, general guidelines,
create, maintain, best practices for
project management.
So we'll have files and historical
information and whatnot to pull from.
They'll coach, mentor,
project managers, because
they always want us to
do and be and get better.
All right.
And as I mentioned already, they will,
the PMO is considered a stakeholder.
on our project and they will set
governance and compliance and ensure that
governance and compliance is being
followed.
All right, so types of PMOs.
First one we see on the next slide is
supportive.
So those are generally like basic PMOs
getting started.
So they'll provide basic templates,
best practices, historical information,
and lessons learned they'll we can consult
with them all right then moving up a notch
to controlling so they'll be supportive
but they also require adherence to the
project management standards methodologies
templates that they are imposing on the
projects and then the most mature PMO is
considered directive so they will directly
control the project They will assign the
PM.
They will ensure that all the standards,
methodologies, templates are being used,
compliance, governance is being followed
on our project.
So they're there to assist
the project manager and again,
make sure we are following
policies and procedures.
Accessing historical
information, lessons learned,
previous similar recently
completed project files.
These are all things that the PMO can
offer, the project managers.